A Guide to the Alice and Phoebe Cary Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6978-c
Alice and Phoebe Cary Collection 1855-1870, n.d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6978-c
ca. 23 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, 1964 May 25
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - "Our spirits seem to me as wines ..." by Alice Cary, 1855 Mar; AMsS, 1 p.
  - "Adelied" by Alice Cary, n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - "Uncertainty" by Phoebe Cary, n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - "Alas" by Phoebe Cary, n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
    [in folder with newspaper clippings under Miscellaneous]
- Letters
  - Alice Cary to Mr. Foster, 1860 Dec 21; ALS, 2 p.
    [Explanation that ill health of others for whom she had to care prevented her from writing.]
  - Alice Cary to "My dear friend", 1862 Mar 6; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions death of friend General [Frederick West] Lander, whose life she characterizes as a "brilliant failure."]
  - Alice Cary to Richard Henry Stoddard, 1866 Oct 21; ALS, 1 p.
    [Compliments his poems and advises him to "stick to what you see and know and feel" as topics for poetry.]
  - Phoebe Cary to "My dear friend", 1869 Feb 25; ALS, 3 p.
    [Is compiling a hymn book with Rev. Dr. Charles F. Deems. ]
  - Phoebe Cary to Emily [Hartley], 1870 Aug 21; ALS, 3 p.
    [Doing some editing-work; took Emily's ms to a publishing house.]
  - Alice Cary to Eddie (nephew), n.y. Apr 18; ALS, 3 p.
    [Writing for the
    Ledger
    and visit from [John Greenleaf] Whittier; her new book is selling well and she mentions plans to publish her poetry in the winter.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Mrs. McKaye, n.y. Apr 21; ALS, 1 p.
    [Complies with request for an autograph.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Mr. Leaver, n.y. Jul 20; ALS, 1 p.
    [Encloses poems for possible public ation, their prices, and return addresses. Also note, possibly by Leaver, which indicates that the poems were not accepted.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Edwin (nephew), n.y. Sep 27; ALS, 3 p.
    [Information from Mr. Owen about private Europe an school "Hofwyl."]
  - Phoebe Cary to [Richard Watson] Gilder, n.y. Nov 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Encloses poem by Charles Deems for review by
    Hours at Home
    . ]
  - Alice Cary to Emily Hartley, n.y. Nov 19; ALS, 4 p.
    [Encourages Emily to send her articles for children on Africa to
    Riverside
    magazine.]
  - Alice Cary to [James Ripley] Osgood, n.d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Asks to have her books sent to Clark, Waggoner & Son and Thurlow Weed, where she hopes they will receive favorable reviews.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Mr. Foster, n.d.; ALS, 1 p.
    [Regrets unable to see him due to Alice's ill health and the absence of Mr. and Mrs. Trillis.]
  - "Anonymous" ( Phoebe Cary) to [ Charles Force Deems], n.d.; ALS, 3 p.
    [Offers advice on Deems' poetry. Explanatory note on verso by Deems.]
- Photographs and prints
  - Alice Cary by J. A. J. Wilson, n.d.; Engraving
  - Alice Cary"from a daguerreotype from life" with same engraving titled, "Miss Alice Cary, first president of Sorosis" by Johnson, Wilson & Co., Publishers, N.Y., n.d.; Engraving
  - Phoebe Cary, Brady's, National Photographic Galleries, Broadway & 10th St. N.Y., n.d.; Original photograph and two engravings
- Miscellaneous
  - Engraving of Phoebe Cary, n.d.; Engraving
  - Newsclippings in bound volume include: Poems by Phoebe Cary, "Thou and I" "A poetic tribute to Susan B. Anthony at her 50th birthday," "Peace," "Nearer Home," "Prayer," and "The Christian's Evening Tide." Several obituary notices of both Alice Cary and Phoebe Cary and an item entitled, "Pleasant Evenings: Reminiscences of the Cary Sisters." Bound volume also includes AMsS for "Alas", 14 newspaper clippings